

**)** +20 109 699 3853

www.johnydev.com

Cairo, Egypt.

### **COVER LETTER**

### DEAR SIR / MADAM,

I am a skilled DevOps Engineer with 2+ years of hands-on experience and total 9 years of experience, an expert in Windows OS, MAC OSX & Linux, with a strong development background.

My target is to master the DevOps culture, currently I am focusing on applying automation, Containerization, Orchestration, CI /CD and Cloud services.

My previous roles in the IT field started with providing level 1 and level 2 technical support as a Sr. System Administrator, troubleshooting, and maintenance of the technology infrastructure and systems for endpoint device management Including win-servers (2003, 2008, 2012), Mac server, firewall Linux server, Render Farm, network management, NAS, SAN, LAN, WAN, RAID, ticketing systems, software distribution, updates, patching virus protection, and imaging.

Then I became an IT Manager, which was more managerial level than technical Starting with Identify the need for upgrades, configurations or new systems and report to the MD, assign tasks, monitor project pipeline, managing servers, during this time i was preparing myself to be a DevOps engineer.

And currently I am a DevOps Engineer responsible for the CI/CD process starting with using Docker to containerize the application, Infrastructure as a Code using Terraform & Ansible, manage containers through Kubernetes and EKS in AWS and run the pipeline using Gitlab CI/CD.

Besides my main experience in the IT field, I have been using Adobe Products as a hobby to design for the past 12 years and Front-End Development for the past 5 years, I am not a Graphic Designer but I have a quite good taste and freelance experience doing different kind of designs, video editing, and websites, you are welcome to check my website <a href="https://www.johnydev.com">www.johnydev.com</a>

I have enclosed my cover letter for your review. I appreciate your time.

Sincerely,

John Bedeir







# JOHN BEDEIR Dev Ops Engineer

**)** +20 109 699 3853

www.johnydev.com

Cairo, Egypt.

# Summary

Skilled DevOps Engineer with 2+ years hands-on experience and total 9 years of experience, in support, system administration, automation and DevOps processes. Focusing area is on applying automation solution have been working in different industries such as Pharmaceutical, Media Production, Online-Trading & IT Services.

And different countries: Egypt, Bulgaria & UAE.

# Sr. Sys Admin

# Linux Sys Admin

# Python

# DevOps

# Automation



### Work Experiences

Jan 2020 - Current

### **DevOps Engineer**

### **Orange Business Services**

Cairo, Egypt

Orange is a French multinational telecommunication corporation.

- Containerize Applications
- · Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery
- Working on ways to automate reports, improve development and release processes
- · Working in Software development life cycle
- Working in AGILE & Concept of Infrastructure as a Code.
- Participating in Front-End Development using JavaScript.
- Project 1: Using Docker to containerize a web app
- Project 2: Build CI/CD automation with GitLab for web app
- Project 3: Manage all build and deploy tools, and oversee all deployments (Kubernetes, Ansible & Jenkins)
- Project 4: Working with AWS using (EC2, IAM, Security groups, ect.)

### Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

### IT MANAGER

### **Yaryor Technologies**

Dubai, UAE

YARYOR is a small company, mostly working on projects that include new technologies like Robotics, Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Digital Signage, Web Development, and Mobile applications.

- · Managing 5 employees
- Monitor performance of information technology systems to determine cost and productivity levels
- Handle annual budget and ensure cost effectiveness
- · Creating scripts to automate tasks

### Mar 2016 - Apr 2018

### SR. SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

### Plus500 BG

♥ Sofia, Bulgaria

Plus 500 is a huge international firm providing online trading, working there was a great opportunity I started there with the Technical Support team then I got promoted to Senior IT providing High-level Support for Windows OS in two offices.

- Provide 24/7 Level 2 Support across all facilities.
- Ensure that helpdesk tickets are closed or escalated promptly.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Symantec endpoint console.
- Monitoring the Server room temperature via sensor.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned.

## Expertise

Linux, Windows & MAC

Docker

**Bash Scripting** 

Vmware, Parrallels & Virtualbox

Git

Web Hosting

HTML5 / CSS3

# CERTIFICATES & SELF-STUDIES

AWS	(Self-Study)
Terraform	(Self-Study)
Kubernetes	(Self-Study)
Jenkins	(Self-Study)
Ansible	(Self-Study)
Vagrant	(Self-Study)
Python	(Self-Study)
RHCSA / RHCE	(Self-Study)
JavaScript	(Self-Study)
MCSA	(Self-Study)





linkedin.com/in/johnbedeir



john.bedeir@gmail.com

## **Work Experiences**

### Jan 2014 - Jul 2015

### SR. SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

### **Aroma Studios**



AROMA is an extraordinary company for media production in the middle east, I got the opportunity for working as a Senior IT with a team of IT providing 24/7 coverage with level 2 crossover platform support Windows OS, Mac OSX, and Linux.

- Level 1 2 Support for all instance (on location, via phone & remotely)
- Install and configure linux and perform system maintenance.
- Ensure pending tasks have been solved.
- Check Kaspersky endpoint security management console and ensure there are no alerts.
- Check the Servers & Renderfarm room temperature.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned

### OTHER SKILLS & **APPS**

**Ubuntu, Mint & CentOs** 

Selenium, RSpec, Capybara

Apache, Nginx, WAMP, **XAMPP** 

FLASK, REST API, SOAP OpenCV

MYSQL, MongoDB

Remote Apps & PDQ Deploy

Xshell / Xftp

WDS & NetInstall

### Sep 2011 - Dec 2013 SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

### Arabcomed



The Arab Company for Medical Products is a factory for manufacturing pharmaceutical this was my first full-time job after graduation providing level 1 help desk support and Create new designs and editing the company website.

- · Level 1 Support on location, via phone or remotely,
- Create New Designs for the next coming product
- Ensure all the endpoint devices are working properly.
- Check the Server room temperature.

### **Education and Certificates**

2015 - 2019

Masters in Computer Science and Engineering

Technical University, Sofia, Bulgaria.

2007 - 2011

**Bachelors in Computer Science** 

Future Academy, Cairo, Egypt.

Volunteering Activity

Member of IT Committee

Enactus Organization, Cairo, Egypt.

### Languages

Arabic	Native
English	Fluent
Bulgarian	Conversational